

Daniel Piechota DevQA Specialist

(+48) 603 158 850

daniel.pi3chota@gmail.com 🔀

Warsaw, Poland

piechotadaniel.com (#

linkedin.com/in/danielpiechota/



About Me

Experienced balance-focused developer with over two years of valuable experience, driven to explore new horizons in the gaming industry. My work is characterized by a methodical, detail-oriented approach and a constant drive for continuous improvement.

Education

2015-2019 Technical High School for Computer Science in Lubliniec

Skills

- Over 20 years of active gaming experience
- Over 2 years of competing at professional level in Battle Royale genre winning more than \$6.200 and accumulated total of \$10.000 revenue in gaming
- Deep, out-of-the-box understanding of game mechanics, allowing for effective reproduction and optimal use in appropriate environments — leading to min-maxing and the burden of optimal play
- Broad practical and theoretical experience across all major game genres, especially live ops titles
- Strong analytical thinking and adaptability, allowing for quick mastery of new gameplay systems, metas and mechanics
- Frequently provide design-focused feedback, offering suggestions for improvements in game design, level design, difficulty scaling, progression, and endgame balance
- Creating feedback on game difficulty, scaling, progression and the end game
- Comfortable navigating evolving in-game environments, including dynamic metas, changing character balance, and weapon tuning.
- Proven fast, self-directed learner, able to take on new responsibilities and grow beyond original role expectations
- Proficient in English (C1 level)—both spoken and written

Work Experience

03.2023 - Present DevQA Specialist



- Responsibility of balancing gameplay abilities from early stage debugging to requesting missing balance levers and supporting features within delivery phases
- Designed and maintained longevity matrices to guide balance and retention across the game lifecycle
- Approached game design holistically, ensuring all systems supported long-term player engagement and cohesion
- Maintained close communication with developers and production to ensure consistent information flow
- Created detailed test plans for progression-related features to ensure stability of implemented systems
- Oversaw the quality of work within Game Design/Balance teams; tracked live features and internal requests, and escalated blockers when necessary
- Acted as a proactive communicator and problemsolver across disciplines, contributing not just feedback but systemic solutions
- Audited progression systems for completeness and functionality; reporting bugs and raising potential red flags or designs oversights
- Deep understanding and knowledge of progression systems, game mechanics, tools and their functionality
- Experience in the VS to Beta stage development of a project, their phases and its life cycle
- As part of development plan I delivered endless runner game project

05.2022 - 03.2023 Junior Balance Tester



- Co-designing Outriders Worldslayer post-launch balance changes
- Limit testing builds to provide more data for balancing effort
- Reading and putting into practice telemetry data
- Preparing feedback on weapons and gameplay
- Creating R&D documentations of modern techs for future projects
- Approaching game from the end-user perspective

Hobbies

- Video games
- Vast form of physical activities
- Competitive gaming and e-sport
- Cognitive science
- Technological innovations
- Streaming